University of California, Los Angeles. Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business records UARC.0458
UCLA Library Special Collections
University of California, Los Angeles. Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business records
1960-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
University of California, Los Angeles. Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business
UARC.0458
42.8 linear feet (107 boxes)
This record series contains materials created by the Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, including correspondence, annual reports, audit materials, staff and committee meeting minutes and agendas, and administrative files.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1992.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9934667623606533
Administrative/ Biographical History
The Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business was created in 1974, serving within the portfolio of the Vice Chancellor for Administration. The Assistant Vice Chancellor was responsible for the oversight of campus Business Services, Extramural Support, Material Management, Communications and Transportation Services, and Housing and Food Services. The position was first occupied by Harland B. Thompson, who generated most of the materials in this record series.
The Administrative Services Division included the Accounting Office, Affirmative Action Office, Campus Architects and Engineers, Cashier's Office, Central Stenography, Environmental Health and Safety, Facilities and Operations, Inventory, Mail and Messenger Service, Office Extramural Support, Personnel Office, Police Department, and Purchasing and Receiving.
Scope and Content
This record series contains materials created by the Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, including correspondence, annual reports, audit materials, staff and committee meeting minutes and agendas, and administrative files. This includes documentation of staff meetings, task forces, campus councils, and professional organizations, such as the Administrative Affairs Council, Business Affairs Council, Capitol Affairs Council, Disability Compliance Task Force, National Association of College and University Business Officers, Policy committee on Sales and Service Activities and Service Enterprise, the Expanded Management Group, Regents' meetings, and others. Also included are administrative files relating to major campus construction projects and long range development plans, facilities and space leasing, audits, transitions to new software and management systems, budgets and financial planning, affirmative action plans, employee relations and union negotiations, and major events such as the 1984 Olympics.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1. Correspondence
Series 2. Annual reports
Series 3. Meeting minutes and agendas
Subseries 3.1. Staff meetings
Subseries 3.2. Committees, councils, and task forces
Series 4. Administrative files
Universities and colleges -- California -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- California -- Business management; Olympic Games (23rd: 1984: Los Angeles, Calif.) Planning; Thompson, Harland B. -- contributor.; University of California, Los Angeles. Office of the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business -- Archives
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1969-1988
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains outgoing correspondence generated by the Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business. Subjects of correspondence are consistent with the issues and projects detailed in the administrative files.
  Subjects of note include the University Policies Commission Task Force on Campus Violence; Federal Anti-Riot Legislation; the creation of the Campus Activities Service Office; the Experimental Police Student Relations Program; the Campus ID system; University property acquisitions and leases; campus housing; the Regents' Action on Campus Emergencies; Campus Disturbance Reports outlining protests, marches, and sit-ins; news of the Kent State massacre; affirmative action and "minority recruitment;" Committee on Campus Press and the TV-Motion Picture Media Production Committee, Chancellor's Cabinet and Division Head meeting minutes, and the Campus Emergency Plan.
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Outgoing, 1969-1970 (Box 72, Folder 2-5)
  - Outgoing, 1970-1971 (Box 84)
  - Outgoing, 1972-1978 (Box 85)
  - Outgoing, 1981-1982 (Box 86)
  - Outgoing, 1982 (Box 87)
  - Outgoing, 1983 (Box 88)
  - Outgoing, 1984-1985 (Box 89)
  - Outgoing, 1985-1986 (Box 90)
  - Outgoing, 1986-1987 (Box 91)
  - Outgoing, 1987-1988 (Box 92)
  - Outgoing, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Annual reports, 1963-1989
  This series contains the annual reports of the UCLA Business Operations Division.
  - Annual reports, 1963-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3-10, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- Series 3: Meeting minutes and agendas, 1970-1990
  This series contains meeting agendas, minutes, notes, and other documentation for staff meetings and the meetings of various committees, councils, and task forces.
  This series has been arranged into two subseries: Staff meetings and Committees, councils, and task forces.
  - Subseries 3.1: Staff meetings, 1970-1990
    This subseries includes meeting agendas, action summaries, minutes and notes, and distributed materials for various offices within the Business Operations Division.
    Materials are arranged alphabetically.
    - Administrative Services, 1972-1973 (Box 93)
    - Administrative Services Division, 1972-1973 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Administrative Services Division division heads, 1970-1972 (Box 48, Folder 1-5)
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1975-1978, 1981-1990 (Box 44, Box 46, Box 47, Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1974-1975 (Box 94)
      Subjects of meetings include budgetary review for the fiscal year; the campus energy crisis (steps to conserve energy by campus), EPA California Transportation Control Plan, CAL/OSHA regulations, parking and transportation, physical plant management and holiday policy, salaries and cost of living increases, and Task Force on Energy Distribution. During this time, the Vice Chancellor's office was also responsible for the Staff Affirmative Action Program. This included oversight of staff Affirmative Action Compliance Committee and Staff Affirmative Action Office.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1975-1976 (Box 95)
      Subjects of meetings include the staff affirmative action program, parking allocations, Public Service Employment Program, annual reports and financial reviews, UCLA Child Care Center, parking and transportation, the Fiscal Analysis Data System (FADS), space needs and assessments, the student housing building program, facilities management, and staff retreats.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1976-1978 (Box 96)
      Subjects of meetings include departmental administration, budgets, annual reports, the Chancellor's Advisory Committee on the Status of Women (CACSW), the Administrative Information Systems taskforce, Administrative Affairs Council, Management Development Program, and communications systems policies.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1978 (Box 97)
      Subjects of meetings include the department's Organization and Functions Manual, Management Effectiveness Program, Business Operations Division budget expenditure report, Management Personnel Evaluation Form, UC Vehicle Purchase policy, Prop 13, campus budget cuts, budget summary for the Vice Chancellor's office, the campus hiring freeze, and internal audits.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1978-1979 (Box 98)
      Subjects of meetings include student employment, telecommunications, administrative reports and operating budgets for the Vice Chancellor's office, the campus internal audit program for business operations, Management Training Program- student services and development division, managerial evaluations, visitor and special parking fees, Affirmative Action program, faculty housing, Prop 13 and budget reductions, and the Vice Chancellor's executive review.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1979-1980 (Box 99)
      Subjects of meetings include the University Staff Compensation Committee report, the Higher Education Employer-Employee Relations Act (HEERA), campus space issues, Regents' Working Capital Fund, departmental operating budgets and audits, 1984 Olympics planning, staff affirmative action program, new campus financial system, campus site planning, and cost accounting.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1980-1982 (Box 100)
      Subjects of meetings include administrative reports, budgetary issues, the departmental grant program, student housing on campus, the South Campus Master Plan, the memorandum of understanding between the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics Organizing Committee and UCLA, Costing and Working Capital for Auxiliary and Service Enterprises, data processing projects, the campus hiring freeze, and legislative budget hearings.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1982-1983 (Box 101)
      Subjects of meetings include the campus hiring freeze (Executive Order B97-82), Facilities Management Deferred Maintenance Program, Systemwide Administration cost reallocation to campus teaching hospitals, Costing and Working Capital for Auxiliary and Service Enterprises, student housing, administrative reports and budgetary issues, a California Educational Television (KCET)/UCLA agreement, and the Westwood Central Plaza/ BruinWalk project. Also included are materials concerning collective bargaining on campus, such as the "UCLA Actions to Resolve Collective Bargaining-Related Problems With Systemwide Administration" report, administrative review and grievances analysis, sample memos encouraging employees to vote for no union representation, and other policy and analysis documents.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1983-1984 (Box 102)
      Subjects of meetings include the 1984 Olympics, administrative reports and budgetary issues, new computer systems, Business Operations Division Expanded Management Group, and the campus master audit plan. Also included are materials related to collective bargaining on campus, such as mailings and bulletins encouraging staff to vote no on union representation, the Bargaining Policy Council, the "Collective Bargaining in the University" conference, information about various unions, collective bargaining training sessions, and nominees and selections for bargaining teams.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1984-1985 (Box 103)
      Subjects of meetings include administrative reports and budgetary issues, the 1984 Olympics, collective bargaining and grievance procedures, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) agreements, facilities and operations, parking and transportation long-range planning, management seminars, the campus audit program, the Business Operations Division annual report, child care services, and the Department of Defense conference at UCLA.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1985-1986 (Box 104)
      Subjects of meetings include management seminars, union negotiations and collective bargaining materials, budget issues and administrative reports, the West Campus Management Plan, transportation planning, campus facilities and operations, and campus child care services.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1986-1987 (Box 105)
      Subjects of meetings include Expanded Management Group activities, management workshops and seminars, budgets, UCLA Technology Transfer Program proposals, salary increases, AFSCME salary negotiations, audits, construction projects, the Chancellors' Conference on Affirmative Action, and the UCLA seismic correction program.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1988 (Box 106)
      Subjects of meetings include staff affirmative action programs, budget reports, administrative reports, campus child care services, a Summary of Facilities Requirements, Business Operations department activities, merit increases, and management workshops.
    - Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1989 (Box 107)
      Subjects of meetings include staff affirmative action programs, Expanded Management Group activities, the Executive Budget Committee, and budgetary and administrative issues.
    - Facilities and Operations, Administrative Services, 1972-1973 (Box 44)
    - Facilities and Operations, Assistant Vice Chancellor for Business, 1973-1975 (Box 44)
    - Facilities and Operations, 1973 (Box 93)
    - Facilities and Operations, 1973-1974 (Box 94)
    - Vice Chancellor for Administration, 1972-1973 (Box 48, Folder 6, Box 49, Box 50, Folder 1-5)
      Includes correspondence, notes, reports, budgets, management plans, campus administrative issues projects.
    - Vice Chancellor for Administration, 1987-1990 (Box 51, Folder 1-2, Box 56, Folder 4-5)
    - Staff seminars: Chester Karass Negotiating Seminar, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Staff seminars: Herbert Kindler Stress Management Seminar, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Staff seminars: Management Interviewing Seminar, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Staff seminars: Managing Diversity Seminar, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3.2: Committees, councils, and task forces, 1971-1990
    This subseries includes meeting minutes, notes, and agendas for various committees, councils, task forces, and working groups.
    Materials are arranged alphabetically by group title.
    - Activities Guidelines Committee, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Affairs council, 1977-1979 (Box 21, Folder 5-8, Box 22, Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Administrators & Supervisors Association (ASA), 1977-1990 (Box 23, Folder 3-6)
    - Affirmative Action & Ethnic Diversity Seminar, 1987-1989 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Business Affairs Council, 1975-1990 (Box 24, Folder 2-6, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Folder 1-3)
    - Campus Graphics Committee, 1977-1983 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Chancellor's Cabinet, 1981-1983 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Chancellor's Cabinet: Lake Arrowhead meeting, 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
    - Capital Affairs Council, 1977-1990 (Box 30, Folder 1-5, Box 31, Box 32)
    - Capital and Space Planning committee, 1981-1989 (Box 32, Folder 6, Box 33, Folder 1-6)
    - Capital Outlay Task Force, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Central/Departmental Administrators, 1980-1990 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
    - Chancellor and Administrators Group meetings, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Community Relations Staff Task Group, 1977-1988 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Disability Compliance Task Force, 1986-1988 (Box 34, Folder 4-5, Box 35, Box 36)
      Includes Action Plans, Evaluation of Access draft report, and Facility Survey.
    - Disability Compliance Task Force: State Accessibility Standards- Interpretive manual, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Diversity Development Team, 1988-1990 (Box 37, Folder 2-4)
    - El Grupo Mariposa, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Expanded Management Group meetings, 1984-1990 (Box 43, Folder 4-7, Box 44)
    - Expanded Management Group: diversity seminars and materials, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
    - Expanded Management Group: meetings and agendas, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 6-7)
    - Management by objectives, 1971-1975 (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
    - National Association of College & University Business Officers (NACUBO), 1980-1987 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - NACUBO/WACUBO, 1981-1990 (Box 38, Folder 1-10)
    - Order of the Golden Bruin, 1976-1986 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Policy committee on Sales & Service Activities & Service Enterprise (POSSSE), 1985-1990 (Box 39, Folder 1-6, Box 40, Box 41)
    - President's Council of Chancellors, 1979-1988 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Procurement Policy: Ad Hoc Committee to Review 1976, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Recharge Policy Committee, 1986-1990 (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    - Recharge Policy Committee (Ad Hoc), 1980-1984 (Box 42, Folder 3-6)
    - Regents' Meetings, 1980-1990 (Box 58, Folder 1-4)
    - Registration Fee Committee, 1980-1983 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Reprographic Equipment and Supply Committee, campus printing services, 1974-1978, 1983-1987 (Box 55, Folder 7-8)
    - "Sherry Sippers Group" Associate Vice Chancellors informal meetings, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Subcommittee on Administrative Information Systems, 1974-1976 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Systemwide Vice Chancellors for Administration meetings, 1980-1990 (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
      Includes reports and correspondence about AB 2546: State Government Competition with Private Enterprise.
    - University Policy commission, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Series 4: Administrative files, 1960-1990
  This series includes correspondence, minutes and notes, reports and proposals, budgets and financial materials, and other documentation relating to various campus activities and projects.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Academic computing, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Academic computing: Administrative Data Processing (ADP) systems and reports, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8-11, Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Academic computing: Administrative Information Systems (AIS), 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Academic computing: Business applications for microcomputers, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Academic computing: Campus backbone network, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Academic computing: Computer system acquisition policy, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Academic computing: Financial management study, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7-9, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Academic computing: Office systems study and needs analysis, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Academic computing: Purchasing/Accounts Payable (PAC) workgroup, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5, Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Academic computing: System development status report, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Academic computing: Three-year Executive Data Processing (EDP) systems and proposals, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5-7, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    Includes materials related to Business Transportation Systems Administration, fleet services, campus parking service, mail and messenger service, office microcomputers, material management and storehouse services, Office of Insurance and Risk Management, and campus computing resources plans.
  - Academic Senate, 1984-1987 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Association, 1982-1989 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - American Association of Universities study of university equipment needs- correspondence, reports, and financials, 1979-1980 (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
  - Administrative Problem Identification- Resolution Project, 1979-1981 (Box 59, Folder 4-8)
    Includes staff recruitment task group report, classification and pay task group report, involuntary separation and procedure task group report, goods and services procurement report, and telecommunications report.
  - Administrative Systems Committee, report on audit issues, 1978-1979 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
  - ASUCLA: Integration into the University, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 3-7)
  - ASUCLA: Food Service Master Plan for the General Campus, 1974-1976 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - ASUCLA: Statement of Understanding of ASUCLA Relationships with the University of California, 1974-1984 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - ASUCLA Services and Enterprises Management Information Systems Plan, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - ASUCLA Rights In Commercial Services to UCLA Clients, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Audits: general, 1980-1987 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Audits: business operations division (BUS-49), 1974-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Audits: internal, 1981, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 3-5)
  - Audits: plan, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Audits: recharges, 1982-1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Audits: reports, 1978-1990 (Box 13, Folder 8-10, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Audits: Deloitte, Haskins & Sells audits, 1978-1984 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
  - Audits: Department of Health Education and Welfare/ Department of Health and Human Services, 1978-1982 (Box 20, Folder 6-7)
  - Audits: ONR Procurement & System Review, 1982-1987 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Audits: Peat, Marwick, Mitchell & Co audit, 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Audits: State audits, 1978-1981 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
  - Automated Teller Machines (ATMs) on campus- reports, correspondence, proposals, 1982-1986 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Barrington Plaza acquisition, 1980-1981 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Building Authority (UCLA), 1983-1984 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Building site planning: west medical campus, child care services, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Business and Finance Bulletins, 1981-1986 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Campus Activities Service Office, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Campus Committee on Transportation, 1985 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Campus Community Safety, 1976-1989 (Box 60, Folder 6-7)
    Includes proposals for a Department of Campus Community Safety, parking enforcement program, and campus foot patrol program.
  - Campus Counsel, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Campus litter issues and newspaper recycling bins, 1979-1982 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Campus maps and tours, 1977-1984 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Campus Services Buildings I and II, 1977-1978 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Campus Strategic Planning: reports and correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
  - Campus transit system: task force, correspondence, proposals, 1973-1976 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Capital Improvement proposals, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Carpeting: UCLA Guidelines for the Purchase of Rugs and Carpeting, 1966-1980 (Box 61, Folder 6-8)
  - Campus core services: Central Chiller- Cogeneration Project, 1985-1988 (Box 64, Folder 1-4)
    Includes documentation about off-campus property acquisitions for core services relocation.
  - Central Ticket Office: feasibility study and implementation, 1975-1979 (Box 64, Folder 5, Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Club California: staff and faculty housing, condominium conversion, 1980-1985 (Box 65, Folder 2-3)
  - Conference Center planning, 1978-1983 (Box 65, Folder 4-6, Box 66, Folder 1-3)
  - Costing policy: direct and indirect, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Delegations of Authority from Chancellor Young, 1977-1987 (Box 66, Folder 4-5, Box 68, Folder 1-4)
  - Doolittle Theater: planning and financial analysis, 1986-1987 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Charles R. Drew Postgraduate Medical School, 1977-1983 (Box 69, Folder 1-3)
  - Employee relations, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Enterprises: Costing and Accounting Practices for Self-Sustaining Activities, 1980 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Facilities Management (UCLA), 1974-1989 (Box 54, Folder 1-4)
    Includes documentation of campus housing issues, building maintenance, central receiving, energy programs, and private contracting policy for staff and services.
  - Federal Systems Committee, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Finance/Accounting- general, 1984-1988 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Finance/Accounting: Short Term Investment Pool program, 1981-1988 (Box 54, Folder 6, Box 55, Folder 1-2)
  - Financial Feasibility of Loan Projects: reports, 1978-1979 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Food procurement practices: state auditor's report, 1973-1978 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Food services facility: LuValle Commons, 1975-1981 (Box 69, Folder 6-7)
  - Food services facility: Potlatch (School of Management), 1977-1984 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Food services facility: School of Engineering, 1976-1978 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Forms coordination process, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - General campus space usage, 1981-1988 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Goodwill games: City of LA bid for 1990/1991 Olympics festival, 1986-1987 (Box 70, Folder 5-6)